<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Albania on first things first</title>
    <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/tags/albania/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Albania on first things first</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>All content © Gordon Burgett, 2014-2015</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 21:36:09 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.gordonburgett.net/tags/albania/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Journal • 2019 - Young Professionals</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/albania/2019_youngprofessionals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 21:36:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/albania/2019_youngprofessionals/</guid>
      <description>The in-between I had a full week in between the Shkoder project and the YP project. I spent half of it working remote and the rest just catching up with friends. I found a really good coffee shop to work from. with a wonderful view.
  Day 1 Sunday July 7 Today my first responsibility was going to get everyone from the airport. Back on the receiving end! I enjoy hosting and it was fun to be able to welcome everyone and get them settled in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journal • 2019 - Shkodra</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/albania/2019_shkodra/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:36:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/albania/2019_shkodra/</guid>
      <description>Day 1 Tuesday June 25 We arrived in Tirana around noon and met Pal at the airport. Glad to be back in country! It&amp;rsquo;s been almost a year since I was here last - too long. We went with Pal to pick up Wes and Daniel at Hotel Sokrat. While there we met with Aldo for a bit. It was nice to catch up with him too! He&amp;rsquo;s tranisitioning to a new role with partnerships, and Pal &amp;amp; Ueda next year will be taking over for him as leader of the Tirana high school ministry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building on The Foundation</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2019/04_summer_projects_2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 14:20:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2019/04_summer_projects_2019/</guid>
      <description>According to the grace of God given to me, like a skilled master builder I laid a foundation, and someone else is building upon it. Let each one take care how he builds upon it. For no one can lay a foundation other than that which is laid, which is Jesus Christ. 1 Corinthians 3:10-11
 What is it that we are building together with our partners in Albania?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acts 29</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2018/07_acts_29_in_albania/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 08:55:43 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2018/07_acts_29_in_albania/</guid>
      <description>This month, while we&amp;rsquo;ve been working on the summer project here in Albania, I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading the book of Acts. I love all the descriptions in the book of Acts of faithful people who were not Apostles. Some of them, like Cornelius the centurion, had been faithful for a very long time, and God answered their prayers powefully.
 About the ninth hour of the day he saw clearly in a vision an angel of God come in and say to him, “Cornelius.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journal • 2018</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/albania/2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:36:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/albania/2018/</guid>
      <description>Day 1 Sunday July 1 We traveled overnight Friday, finally arriving Saturday night. After checking into the hotel I was beat. I went to sleep right away and managed to sleep 9 hours straight. It was good though to see Berti, Pal, Ueda, and Aldo, who all picked us up at the airport.
Berti invited me to his bible study group before church. I met up with them at 8am at Mon Cheri.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparing for the Summer</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2018/04_upcoming_summer_project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 20:18:22 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2018/04_upcoming_summer_project/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s that time again! We&amp;rsquo;ve begun preparing to go back to Albania this summer!
Looking forward to going back I&amp;rsquo;m so glad that I already had a chance to get back to Albania in December, when we put on a men&amp;rsquo;s conference for Cornerstone Church of Tirana. That was a great time of fun and fellowship with many of my close Albanian friends. I&amp;rsquo;ve been keeping in touch with them although it&amp;rsquo;s been difficult due to the time difference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Men&#39;s Retreat in Albania</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2017/12_mens_retreat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 20:18:22 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2017/12_mens_retreat/</guid>
      <description>When I look back on my experience with Albania, starting from my first trip there in 2013 until now, I can&amp;rsquo;t help but be amazed at the way God has used this partnership to bring change not only in my life but in the lives of my friends. My key verse for my 2-year stint in Albania was Mark 10:29-30
 “Truly I tell you,” Jesus replied, “no one who has left home or brothers or sisters or mother or father or children or fields for me and the gospel will fail to receive a hundred times as much in this present age: homes, brothers, sisters, mothers, children and fields—along with persecutions—and in the age to come eternal life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Not Done Yet!</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2017/10_nothings_over/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 20:28:57 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2017/10_nothings_over/</guid>
      <description>Hey Y&amp;rsquo;all! It&amp;rsquo;s been a while! I&amp;rsquo;ve been busy with settling in to my new job and routine with Watermark. It&amp;rsquo;s a really great place to work and I feel super blessed to have the opportunity to join staff there! But even as I readjust to life in America I&amp;rsquo;m still looking back to Albania and my next opportunity to go.
And the Lord graciously provides! I will be going on a trip in December with Will Noll, Matt Rial, Chris Hyland, and hopefully 1 to 2 others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2017/07_home/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 11:38:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2017/07_home/</guid>
      <description>My journal for the 2017 project is up!
  photo by Lauren Dean  End of the road All good things come to an end, and my STINT in Albania is no different. On 7 August I fly back to Dallas to spend at least 1 year there, with the hope that I&amp;rsquo;ll return to live in Albania sooner rather than later. At this point I&amp;rsquo;m holding all my plans loosely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journal • 2017</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/albania/2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 21:36:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/albania/2017/</guid>
      <description>photo by Lauren Dean  Day 1 Sunday July 2 Today was a travel day for the others, fortunately I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to travel :). I got to go to church and have a nice afternoon coffee with a friend. We went to go pick up the group at the airport at 5:00, but the plane was delayed a bit. We had a good coffee at the airport waiting for them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Decision</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2017/06_big_decision/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2017 19:50:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2017/06_big_decision/</guid>
      <description>So, I&amp;rsquo;ve got an announcement to make. These past several months I&amp;rsquo;ve been exploring two options for my time after my STINT is up. One area I was exploring was with the Digital Strategies team in Albania, working for Afrim Karoshi. I went to a conference with the Digital Strategies team here in May as part of that exploration. The second area was an open position at Watermark Community Church as a programmer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Leadership</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2017/05_digital_leadership/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 13:39:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2017/05_digital_leadership/</guid>
      <description>April was a fairly slow month. We had our normal schedule of a professional meeting and a social time. This month we had fewer people than normal, but we had a lot of new people which was very interesting. I&amp;rsquo;ve had several opportunities to follow up with contacts, though this appears to be a busy time of year for most of the professionals. We are trying more to model the follow-up process for our partners, inviting them into these meetings and giving them opportunities to lead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>March Project</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2017/04_march_project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 22:08:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2017/04_march_project/</guid>
      <description>We love momentum March 13-17 was a big week for us. We invited a group from Louisville, TX To join us for a week-long momentum building project. This group had an amazing impact, we drew in well over 100 people for the seminar, and our social time was a big success as well. We got a lot of new contacts and, as was our goal, we will be following up with them over the coming weeks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TraNet 2017</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2017/03_tranet_2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 14:36:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2017/03_tranet_2017/</guid>
      <description>What a great weekend! This past weekend we went to Cyprus for a conference about reaching leaders and influencers for Christ. The group was about 28 people, including 10 professionals, 4 teachers, two businesswomen and a government worker. It was a great time of learning and inspiring our partners to reach their peers for Christ.
One speaker was a bible teacher who took us through the book of Mark, highlighting the disciples&amp;rsquo; stories and their leadership journeys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuing Resolve</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2017/02_continuing_resolve/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2017 19:05:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2017/02_continuing_resolve/</guid>
      <description>Lots of stuff has happened this past month! Last I posted I was in the middle of a 2-week break in Dallas. That was a great and relaxing time for me, helped me to prepare mentally and spiritually for these next 7 months in Albania. I saw friends and family and enjoyed plenty of tacos.
When I got back it was right back into the swing of things with a seminar the next day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merry Christmas</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2016/12_merry_christmas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2016 04:56:31 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2016/12_merry_christmas/</guid>
      <description>Merry Christmas to everybody!
I love Christmas time, spending time with family, listening to the Advent messages at church, and especially the Christmas hymns. My favorite is &amp;lsquo;O Holy Night&amp;rsquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s my favorite because it speaks of the hope that came into the world when Jesus Christ was born. Hope is an elusive thing. Lots of people lose hope when what they desire becomes impossible, or even worse, when they get exactly what they wanted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When you eat chili 3 days in a row</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2016/11_too_much_chili/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 14:29:43 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2016/11_too_much_chili/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve been working on follow up since Momentum Europe. We&amp;rsquo;ve had some good meetings with people, and had some good conversations. Of course our goal is to help our partners to do that more and more - to have the conversations that lead to Gospel presentations, to encourage them to share with and invite more people, and to build their confidence.
To that end we organized a training conference this past weekend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Momentum Europe</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2016/10_momentum_europe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2016 23:06:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2016/10_momentum_europe/</guid>
      <description>September and October have been pretty slow months, as we plan and gear up for our first big event, Momentum Europe. I&amp;rsquo;ve been busying myself with a lot of administrative work, but we&amp;rsquo;ve also had opportunity to begin training our committed believers.
Bursting your Bubble In my opinion, our greatest success last year was finding 8 believers who have decided to commit to being part of our ministry. One of the things we asked of them is to commit to be trained in evangelism by our staff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer Recap</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2016/08_summer_recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2016 15:30:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2016/08_summer_recap/</guid>
      <description>Well, it&amp;rsquo;s been a crazy couple months! When I last posted we were about to start Ice and Spice, CRU Albania&amp;rsquo;s summer camp for high school students. As part of my role on the LLM team, I was also helping out with an International School Project conference for teachers and principals. So I was already a little worn out when Ice and Spice started! But I got energized when my friends arrived from Texas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journal • 2016 - Ice And Spice</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/albania/2016_iceandspice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2016 21:36:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/albania/2016_iceandspice/</guid>
      <description>photo by Ron Acord  Day 1 Monday June 27 This year things have been a bit different, but I&amp;rsquo;m trying as much as possible to feel like I&amp;rsquo;m part of the American group. For the first 2 days though I also have some other responsibilities. My ministry team here in Albania, Leader-Led Movements, has a 2-day evangelistic conference called Life Choices. The graciously allowed me to go do Ice and Spice instead, but I still want to help them set up and tear down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journal • 2016 - Young Professionals</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/albania/2016_youngprofessionals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2016 21:36:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/albania/2016_youngprofessionals/</guid>
      <description>Day 1 Monday July 4 Today was a nice break. We canceled the morning trip to Kruja, because all the Americans (including me) were worn out from the high schoolers. I slept in till about 9:30, then camped out with Wes and Chris at Mulliri Vjeter. They had to finish working on last minute changes to their presentations. We met up with the staff team for a relaxing lunch. The American team and staff got introduced to each-other and we had a nice relaxing time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s Summertime!</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2016/06_its_summer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2016 14:33:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2016/06_its_summer/</guid>
      <description>What time is it? It&amp;rsquo;s summertime!  It&amp;rsquo;s about time for Ice and Spice, the annual summer camp for high school students here in Tirana! My friends and I have been helping with this camp since the first time I came to Tirana, way back in 2013. A lot has changed since then! Albania Fried Chicken went out of business, but there&amp;rsquo;s now a legit KFC at the mall (Albania has only one mall).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Refreshed and Ready</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2016/06_refreshed_and_ready/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2016 11:49:34 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2016/06_refreshed_and_ready/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s always great to go home. I&amp;rsquo;ve had multiple definitions of &amp;ldquo;home&amp;rdquo; over the years, but right now the place I most identify as &amp;ldquo;home&amp;rdquo; is Dallas. Having just spent 5 weeks there, I can totally confirm that is still the case.
Since I&amp;rsquo;ve committed to a second year here, I felt the need to go home and ask my supporters to commit to a second year with me. This was the perfect time to do it, since my cousin was getting married on June 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Happy Place</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2016/05_my_happy_place/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2016 11:59:12 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2016/05_my_happy_place/</guid>
      <description>This is my happy place Lake Lyndon B. Johnson, about 45 minutes west of Austin. A beautiful constant-level freshwater lake. My grandmother has owned a lakehouse here for more than 30 years. My family and I vacationed here almost every summer. If there were no Good News to preach, I would as much as possible spend my time here.
 Now I would remind you, brothers, of the gospel I preached to you, which you received, in which you stand, and by which you are being saved, if you hold fast to the word I preached to you—unless you believed in vain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6 Months and Counting</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2016/04_six_months_and_counting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 17:15:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2016/04_six_months_and_counting/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re moving into the spring now, and as I&amp;rsquo;m preparing to go back to Dallas for a 1 month fundraising trip, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d reflect on where we are after 6 months.
Towards the Goal We have a growing number of contacts now, young professional believers who have been joining us for seminars and other activities. We&amp;rsquo;ve had a couple of vision casting meetings with them too. Word is beginning to get around that this is a place to continue what they were doing with student ministries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shift musical</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2016/03_shift_musical/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 17:56:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2016/03_shift_musical/</guid>
      <description>We got to see a really cool musical event this week! A big group of high school students from Colorado came to perform their evangelistic musical, &amp;ldquo;SHIFT&amp;rdquo;.
 CRU&amp;rsquo;s high school and college ministries invited a lot of students from all around Tirana. I even saw the Elbasan kids show up. Our young professionals all went and sat together near the front. It was pretty awesome to see how many people showed up!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sometimes It&#39;s Tough</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2016/02_sometimes_its_tough/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2016 14:35:52 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2016/02_sometimes_its_tough/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve posted a lot about the good times recently on this blog, but I thought with this post I&amp;rsquo;d let y&amp;rsquo;all in on the tough parts. Like any job it&amp;rsquo;s got ups and downs. Sometimes you work real hard for what seems like minimal gain. Sometimes you have all these cool plans and they get interrupted by something out of your control. Especially when your job is people.
This past week was tough for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring and Networking</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2016/01_exploring-and-networking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 22:02:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2016/01_exploring-and-networking/</guid>
      <description>This past week I went to the STINT Mid-Year conference in Málaga, Spain. It was a lot of fun to hang out with a bunch of Americans! I didn&amp;rsquo;t know anyone when I got there, but by the end I had made several friends. The beachfront was beautiful, especially the late sunrise over the Mediterranean. I was excited to play a bunch of Ultimate Frisbee, since I hadn&amp;rsquo;t played for several months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The first 3 months</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2015/12_the_first_3_months/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2015 13:49:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2015/12_the_first_3_months/</guid>
      <description>I want to spend some time in this blog post unpacking what I&amp;rsquo;ve felt, what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned, and what I&amp;rsquo;ve found here in the past almost 3 months since I came to Albania. I really can&amp;rsquo;t believe time has gone by so fast. There&amp;rsquo;s so much to do, and so many new friends that it&amp;rsquo;s never boring. Is this what I want to do with the rest of my life? I can&amp;rsquo;t answer that yet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome Weekend</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2015/12_welcome_weekend/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2015 20:31:24 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2015/12_welcome_weekend/</guid>
      <description>What a great weekend! This weekend we had some visitors from Dallas. Rick Howard, the missions pastor for Watermark, and Cheryl Boyd came to visit. It was great to see them, to be encouraged by some friends from home. I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking forward to this for a while!
Cheryl has been in Eastern Europe with CRU for 12+ years, and so she knew a lot of CRU staff here in Albania.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Newsletter • Dec 1 2015</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/newsletter/01-12-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/newsletter/01-12-2015/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remaining Humble</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2015/11_remaining_humble/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 10:31:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2015/11_remaining_humble/</guid>
      <description>This week we had our first young-professionals meeting! We had 17 people come to hear Dennis Beck speak on worldview. He did a great job telling stories which got the participants to think. He has a talent for conveying these high concepts in story form. The discussion went well also. I sat at a table with a few young professionals. Two of them are believers from Fabi&amp;rsquo;s church. The other was Dejvis, with whom I&amp;rsquo;ve been building a relationship.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Newsletter • Nov 3 2015</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/newsletter/03-11-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2015 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/newsletter/03-11-2015/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slow Going</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2015/10_slow-going/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2015 14:35:49 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2015/10_slow-going/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been in Albania now almost 3 weeks. Prior to now, the longest I&amp;rsquo;d ever been outside the US was 10 days. It definitely feels strange, knowing I&amp;rsquo;ll be here probably 6 or 7 more months before I make a trip back to Dallas. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of things I&amp;rsquo;ve been missing - including having a clothes dryer and a dishwasher. I saw some pictures of friends going to the State Fair, and I felt a bit homesick.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 1 in Albania</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2015/09_day-1-in-albania/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 15:15:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2015/09_day-1-in-albania/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m here!
 It&amp;rsquo;s just as I remember it. All the buildings, streets, people. It almost feels like a 2nd home. I arrived at 2:30pm, and was picked up by my team leader Illir Stavro. He dropped me off at my apartment, which I&amp;rsquo;m sharing with two new members of the high-school ministry team: Gedis and Pal. It&amp;rsquo;s a nice, small apartment. I have my own room, and there&amp;rsquo;s a living area with a couch and a small bathroom and kitchen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Newsletter • Sep 26 2015</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/newsletter/26-9-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2015 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/newsletter/26-9-2015/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fully funded!</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2015/08_fully-funded/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 20:40:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2015/08_fully-funded/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to a good friend hosting an event last weekend, I have now reached my monthly goal! And I have some room to spare! I&amp;rsquo;m really thankful for everyone who&amp;rsquo;s contributed to help me. I&amp;rsquo;m excited to finalize my plans to begin this journey!
Speaking of which, I bought my plane tickets today! First time I&amp;rsquo;ve ever bought a one-way flight. But it&amp;rsquo;s locked in now. I fly from Dallas to Washington D.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journal • 2015</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/albania/2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2015 21:36:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/albania/2015/</guid>
      <description>photo by Ron Acord  Day 1 Thursday July 2 Back for a third time! Kinda hard to believe we got 20 people. We have 2 teams full of great people and we&amp;rsquo;re here and ready to rumble. Will and Lauren are leading one team of 10 that&amp;rsquo;s staying in Tirana, while Lucy and I lead the team that will depart to Elbasan on Sunday. Getting here was much better than last year, thanks mostly to Lucy&amp;rsquo;s organizational leadership and Will&amp;rsquo;s being on the ball with prep.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almost time</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2015/06_almost-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2015 21:38:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2015/06_almost-time/</guid>
      <description>In less than 2 weeks, I&amp;rsquo;ll be in Albania :) This time just for 2 weeks, but I&amp;rsquo;m ready to go for good. But, all things in their time:
 There is a time for everything,
and a season for every activity under the heavens:
a time to be born and a time to die,
a time to plant and a time to uproot,
a time to kill and a time to heal,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Albania!  YEEEEHAWWW!</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/albania/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 22:20:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/albania/</guid>
      <description>Howdy! My name is Gordon Burgett and I&amp;rsquo;m going to Albania this summer. I first went in the summer of 2013, and fell in love with both the people and the mission. Since that time I’ve been back and forth every summer, and a few stints in between.
This summer, we&amp;rsquo;re continuing the work we&amp;rsquo;ve been doing over the past 7+ years. As the Poland Re:Generation project matures, we&amp;rsquo;re starting to look into new ways we can support the native staff and church members in Albania and beyond.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Euro Trip!</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2015/01_euro-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 10:20:47 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2015/01_euro-trip/</guid>
      <description>The best part is it&amp;rsquo;s only half over! I&amp;rsquo;m writing this post from the home of my good friend Aldo Rustemi, in Tirana the capital city of Albania. So much has happened, and so much more is to come. It&amp;rsquo;s awesome :)
Wien, Österreich We began the trip in Vienna, where we went sightseeing just the three of us (me, Lucy and Chris). Vienna in the winter is amazing, especially when there&amp;rsquo;s snow on the ground.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journal • 2014</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/albania/2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2014 21:36:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/albania/2014/</guid>
      <description>Travel Days July 12-13 We flew overnight on Austrian airways, leaving early morning on the 12th with a layover at Washington Dulles. We were all tired, but some of us were awake enough to go out to the National Air and Space museum Udvar-Hazy center for a couple hours. My dad decided to meet us there, since my parents live in Washington DC. He, my little sister Alina and I hung out with Will, Danita, and Ron at the museum, which was pretty awesome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journal • 2013</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/albania/2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2013 21:36:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/albania/2013/</guid>
      <description>Day 1 Thursday July 18 I don&amp;rsquo;t even know why God brought us down here. What more can we do that He&amp;rsquo;s not already doing? Today we got off the plane, and found out our luggage won&amp;rsquo;t arrive until tomorrow. We rode into town with a nice guy who picked us up. We were met at the hotel by Aldo, who is one of the leaders of Ice and Spice.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>