<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>first things first on first things first</title>
    <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content in first things first on first things first</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>All content © Gordon Burgett, 2014-2015</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 08:55:43 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Acts 29</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2018/07_acts_29_in_albania/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 08:55:43 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2018/07_acts_29_in_albania/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This month, while we&amp;rsquo;ve been working on the summer project here in Albania, I&amp;rsquo;ve
been reading the book of Acts.  I love all the descriptions in the book of Acts
of faithful people who were not Apostles.  Some of them, like Cornelius the centurion,
had been faithful for a very long time, and God answered their prayers powefully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the ninth hour of the day he saw clearly in a vision an angel of God come in
and say to him, “Cornelius.” And he stared at...</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparing for the Summer</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2018/04_upcoming_summer_project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 20:18:22 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2018/04_upcoming_summer_project/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s that time again!  We&amp;rsquo;ve begun preparing to go back to Albania this summer!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.gordonburgett.net/.640x/images/2018/2018_albania_group_photo_social.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;2018 team photo&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;looking-forward-to-going-back&#34;&gt;Looking forward to going back&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m so glad that I already had a chance to get back to Albania in December,
when we put on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2017/12_mens_retreat/&#34;&gt;a men&amp;rsquo;s conference for Cornerstone Church of Tirana&lt;/a&gt;.
That was a great time o...</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Men&#39;s Retreat in Albania</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2017/12_mens_retreat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 20:18:22 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2017/12_mens_retreat/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;When I look back on my experience with Albania, starting from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gordonburgett.net/albania/2013&#34;&gt;my first trip there in 2013&lt;/a&gt;
until now, I can&amp;rsquo;t help but be amazed at the way God has used this partnership to bring
change not only in my life but in the lives of my friends.  My key verse for my 2-year stint
in Albania was Mark 10:29-30&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Truly I tell you,” Jesus replied, “no one who has left home or brothers or sisters or
mother or father or children or fields for me a...</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Not Done Yet!</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2017/10_nothings_over/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 20:28:57 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2017/10_nothings_over/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey Y&amp;rsquo;all!  It&amp;rsquo;s been a while!  I&amp;rsquo;ve been busy with settling in to my new job and routine with Watermark.
It&amp;rsquo;s a really great place to work and I feel super blessed to have the opportunity to join staff there!
But even as I readjust to life in America I&amp;rsquo;m still looking back to Albania and my next opportunity to
go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the Lord graciously provides!  I will be going on a trip in December with Will Noll, Matt Rial,
Chris Hyland, and hopefully 1 to 2 others....</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Home</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2017/07_home/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 11:38:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2017/07_home/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gordonburgett.net/albania/2017&#34;&gt;My journal for the 2017 project is up!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gordonburgett.net/albania/2017&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://www.gordonburgett.net/.640x/images/2017/2017_07_retreat.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Summer retreat group&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;attribution&#34;&gt;photo by Lauren Dean&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;end-of-the-road&#34;&gt;End of the road&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All good things come to an end, and my STINT in Albania is no different.  On 7 August I fly back to Dallas to spend at least 1 year there, with the hope that I&amp;rsquo;ll return to live in ...</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Decision</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2017/06_big_decision/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2017 19:50:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2017/06_big_decision/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;So, I&amp;rsquo;ve got an announcement to make.  These past several months I&amp;rsquo;ve been exploring two options for my time after my STINT is up.  One area I was exploring was with the Digital Strategies team in Albania, working for Afrim Karoshi.  I went to a conference with the Digital Strategies team here in May as part of that exploration.  The second area was an open position at Watermark Community Church as a programmer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The big news is I decided to go with the Watermark position...</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Leadership</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2017/05_digital_leadership/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 13:39:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2017/05_digital_leadership/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;April was a fairly slow month.  We had our normal schedule of a professional meeting and a social time.  This month we had fewer people than normal, but we had a lot of new people which was very interesting.  I&amp;rsquo;ve had several opportunities to follow up with contacts, though this appears to be a busy time of year for most of the professionals.  We are trying more to model the follow-up process for our partners, inviting them into these meetings and giving them opportunities to lead.  A...</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>March Project</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2017/04_march_project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 22:08:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2017/04_march_project/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-love-momentum&#34;&gt;We love momentum&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;March 13-17 was a big week for us.  We invited a group from Louisville, TX To join us for a week-long momentum building project.  This group had an amazing impact, we drew in well over 100 people for the seminar, and our social time was a big success as well.  We got a lot of new contacts and, as was our goal, we will be following up with them over the coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The group featured Paul Henry, former finance director for the Kimber...</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>TraNet 2017</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2017/03_tranet_2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 14:36:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2017/03_tranet_2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What a great weekend!  This past weekend we went to Cyprus for a conference about reaching leaders and influencers for Christ.  The group was about 28 people, including 10 professionals, 4 teachers, two businesswomen and a government worker.  It was a great time of learning and inspiring our partners to reach their peers for Christ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.gordonburgett.net/.640x/images/2017/tranet_2017/group_pic.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Group pic&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One speaker was a bible teacher who took us through the book of Mark, h...</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
