<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Albania on first things first</title>
    <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/categories/albania/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Albania on first things first</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>All content © Gordon Burgett, 2014-2015</copyright>
    <atom:link href="/categories/albania/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Men&#39;s Retreat in Albania</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2017/12_mens_retreat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 20:18:22 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2017/12_mens_retreat/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;When I look back on my experience with Albania, starting from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gordonburgett.net/albania/2013&#34;&gt;my first trip there in 2013&lt;/a&gt;
until now, I can&amp;rsquo;t help but be amazed at the way God has used this partnership to bring
change not only in my life but in the lives of my friends.  My key verse for my 2-year stint
in Albania was Mark 10:29-30&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Truly I tell you,” Jesus replied, “no one who has left home or brothers or sisters or
mother or father or children or fields for me a...</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Not Done Yet!</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2017/10_nothings_over/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 20:28:57 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2017/10_nothings_over/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey Y&amp;rsquo;all!  It&amp;rsquo;s been a while!  I&amp;rsquo;ve been busy with settling in to my new job and routine with Watermark.
It&amp;rsquo;s a really great place to work and I feel super blessed to have the opportunity to join staff there!
But even as I readjust to life in America I&amp;rsquo;m still looking back to Albania and my next opportunity to
go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the Lord graciously provides!  I will be going on a trip in December with Will Noll, Matt Rial,
Chris Hyland, and hopefully 1 to 2 others....</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Home</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2017/07_home/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 11:38:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2017/07_home/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gordonburgett.net/albania/2017&#34;&gt;My journal for the 2017 project is up!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gordonburgett.net/albania/2017&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://www.gordonburgett.net/.640x/images/2017/2017_07_retreat.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Summer retreat group&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;attribution&#34;&gt;photo by Lauren Dean&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;end-of-the-road&#34;&gt;End of the road&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All good things come to an end, and my STINT in Albania is no different.  On 7 August I fly back to Dallas to spend at least 1 year there, with the hope that I&amp;rsquo;ll return to live in ...</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Decision</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2017/06_big_decision/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2017 19:50:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2017/06_big_decision/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;So, I&amp;rsquo;ve got an announcement to make.  These past several months I&amp;rsquo;ve been exploring two options for my time after my STINT is up.  One area I was exploring was with the Digital Strategies team in Albania, working for Afrim Karoshi.  I went to a conference with the Digital Strategies team here in May as part of that exploration.  The second area was an open position at Watermark Community Church as a programmer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The big news is I decided to go with the Watermark position...</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Leadership</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2017/05_digital_leadership/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 13:39:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2017/05_digital_leadership/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;April was a fairly slow month.  We had our normal schedule of a professional meeting and a social time.  This month we had fewer people than normal, but we had a lot of new people which was very interesting.  I&amp;rsquo;ve had several opportunities to follow up with contacts, though this appears to be a busy time of year for most of the professionals.  We are trying more to model the follow-up process for our partners, inviting them into these meetings and giving them opportunities to lead.  A...</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>March Project</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2017/04_march_project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 22:08:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2017/04_march_project/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-love-momentum&#34;&gt;We love momentum&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;March 13-17 was a big week for us.  We invited a group from Louisville, TX To join us for a week-long momentum building project.  This group had an amazing impact, we drew in well over 100 people for the seminar, and our social time was a big success as well.  We got a lot of new contacts and, as was our goal, we will be following up with them over the coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The group featured Paul Henry, former finance director for the Kimber...</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>TraNet 2017</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2017/03_tranet_2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 14:36:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2017/03_tranet_2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What a great weekend!  This past weekend we went to Cyprus for a conference about reaching leaders and influencers for Christ.  The group was about 28 people, including 10 professionals, 4 teachers, two businesswomen and a government worker.  It was a great time of learning and inspiring our partners to reach their peers for Christ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.gordonburgett.net/.640x/images/2017/tranet_2017/group_pic.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Group pic&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One speaker was a bible teacher who took us through the book of Mark, h...</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuing Resolve</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2017/02_continuing_resolve/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2017 19:05:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2017/02_continuing_resolve/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Lots of stuff has happened this past month!  Last I posted I was in the middle
of a 2-week break in Dallas.  That was a great and relaxing time for me, helped
me to prepare mentally and spiritually for these next 7 months in Albania. I
saw friends and family and enjoyed plenty of tacos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I got back it was right back into the swing of things with a seminar the
next day.  It was a video seminar, we showed &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.willowcreek.com/events/leadership/2016-domestic-b/#facul...</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Merry Christmas</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2016/12_merry_christmas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2016 04:56:31 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2016/12_merry_christmas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Merry Christmas to everybody!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love Christmas time, spending time with family, listening to the Advent messages at church, and especially the Christmas hymns.  My favorite is &amp;lsquo;O Holy Night&amp;rsquo;.  It&amp;rsquo;s my favorite because it speaks of the hope that came into the world when Jesus Christ was born.  Hope is an elusive thing.  Lots of people lose hope when what they desire becomes impossible, or even worse, when they get exactly what they wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most young professio...</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>When you eat chili 3 days in a row</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2016/11_too_much_chili/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 14:29:43 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2016/11_too_much_chili/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve been working on follow up since Momentum Europe.  We&amp;rsquo;ve had some good
meetings with people, and had some good conversations.  Of course our goal is
to help our partners to do that more and more - to have the conversations that
lead to Gospel presentations, to encourage them to share with and invite
more people, and to build their confidence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.gordonburgett.net/images/2016/yps_byb_1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;professionals on the beach in Durres&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To that end we organized a training...</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Momentum Europe</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2016/10_momentum_europe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2016 23:06:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2016/10_momentum_europe/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;September and October have been pretty slow months, as we plan and gear up for our
first big event, Momentum Europe.  I&amp;rsquo;ve been busying myself with a lot of administrative
work, but we&amp;rsquo;ve also had opportunity to begin training our committed believers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;bursting-your-bubble&#34;&gt;Bursting your Bubble&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, our greatest success last year was finding 8 believers who have decided
to commit to being part of our ministry.  One of the things we asked of them is...</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer Recap</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2016/08_summer_recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2016 15:30:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2016/08_summer_recap/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Well, it&amp;rsquo;s been a crazy couple months!  When I last posted we were about to start Ice and Spice, CRU Albania&amp;rsquo;s summer camp for high school students.  As part of my role on the LLM team, I was also helping out with an International School Project conference for teachers and principals.  So I was already a little worn out when Ice and Spice started!  But I got energized when my friends arrived from Texas.  It was a great week, filled with a lot of good conversations with high scho...</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
