<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hosting on first things first</title><link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/categories/hosting/</link><description>Recent content in Hosting on first things first</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>All content © Gordon Burgett, 2014-2015</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2015 20:33:41 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://www.gordonburgett.net/categories/hosting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Running with Docker</title><link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2015/10_running_with_docker/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2015 20:33:41 +0200</pubDate><guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2015/10_running_with_docker/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="locked-out">Locked out!&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I managed to lock myself out of my EC2 instance when I was managing my keys. So in order to update my blog, I had to deploy it to a new EC2 instance. I decided to take the opportunity to improve the way I&amp;rsquo;m deploying new versions of my site.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Note: This will be a technical post. If you&amp;rsquo;re following along with my adventure in Albania, you can skip this one.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Migrating to Node</title><link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2015/04_migrating-to-node/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2015 23:23:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2015/04_migrating-to-node/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="so-i-wanted-an-app-server">So I wanted an app server.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>How hard could it be right? Well, not really that hard at all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was tired of having a static site served by apache. I want to do some cool stuff with the google APIs, like maybe a form submit where the results end up in a google doc for me. To do that I need more than hugo&amp;rsquo;s static site generation. But I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to get rid of hugo because I like a lot of it&amp;rsquo;s features, so I added nodejs on top of it as the application server.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>hosting the blog</title><link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2014/12_hosting-the-blog/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2014 18:42:21 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2014/12_hosting-the-blog/</guid><description>&lt;p>I decided to use Amazon EC2 to host the blog, because they give you 1 year free on a micro instance. Plus I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to learn how to host something on Amazon&amp;rsquo;s cloud. I&amp;rsquo;ll get a linux instance and put an Apache HTTP server on it. Should be easy enough to do.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s my EC2 management console after signing up for an Amazon account and creating a linux micro instance:
![EC2 Management console](/images/2014/EC2 management console.png)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Creating a blog</title><link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2014/12_creating-a-blog/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2014 13:52:12 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2014/12_creating-a-blog/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="well-here-it-is">Well, here it is.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to create a blog for a while. I don&amp;rsquo;t know what it will look like in the future, or how often I&amp;rsquo;ll update it, but as I sit here writing it it&amp;rsquo;s kind of cathartic. It would be good to get some thoughts out there, and if anybody reads it that&amp;rsquo;s a bonus.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I want to talk about anything and everything on this blog. I&amp;rsquo;ll delve into my work, hopefully some of these pages will be useful when another developer types some obscure error code into google. I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss my faith, hopefully that could spark some interesting discussion. I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss the important stuff that happens in my life, hopefully someone might find it interesting.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>