<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Missions on first things first</title>
    <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/categories/missions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Missions on first things first</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>All content © Gordon Burgett, 2014-2015</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:36:09 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.gordonburgett.net/categories/missions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Journal • 2018</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/albania/2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:36:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/albania/2018/</guid>
      <description>Day 1 Sunday July 1 We traveled overnight Friday, finally arriving Saturday night. After checking into the hotel I was beat. I went to sleep right away and managed to sleep 9 hours straight. It was good though to see Berti, Pal, Ueda, and Aldo, who all picked us up at the airport.
Berti invited me to his bible study group before church. I met up with them at 8am at Mon Cheri.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journal • 2017</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/albania/2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 21:36:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/albania/2017/</guid>
      <description>photo by Lauren Dean  Day 1 Sunday July 2 Today was a travel day for the others, fortunately I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to travel :). I got to go to church and have a nice afternoon coffee with a friend. We went to go pick up the group at the airport at 5:00, but the plane was delayed a bit. We had a good coffee at the airport waiting for them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journal • 2016 - Ice And Spice</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/albania/2016_iceandspice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2016 21:36:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/albania/2016_iceandspice/</guid>
      <description>photo by Ron Acord  Day 1 Monday June 27 This year things have been a bit different, but I&amp;rsquo;m trying as much as possible to feel like I&amp;rsquo;m part of the American group. For the first 2 days though I also have some other responsibilities. My ministry team here in Albania, Leader-Led Movements, has a 2-day evangelistic conference called Life Choices. The graciously allowed me to go do Ice and Spice instead, but I still want to help them set up and tear down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journal • 2016 - Young Professionals</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/albania/2016_youngprofessionals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2016 21:36:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/albania/2016_youngprofessionals/</guid>
      <description>Day 1 Monday July 4 Today was a nice break. We canceled the morning trip to Kruja, because all the Americans (including me) were worn out from the high schoolers. I slept in till about 9:30, then camped out with Wes and Chris at Mulliri Vjeter. They had to finish working on last minute changes to their presentations. We met up with the staff team for a relaxing lunch. The American team and staff got introduced to each-other and we had a nice relaxing time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fully funded!</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2015/08_fully-funded/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 20:40:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2015/08_fully-funded/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to a good friend hosting an event last weekend, I have now reached my monthly goal! And I have some room to spare! I&amp;rsquo;m really thankful for everyone who&amp;rsquo;s contributed to help me. I&amp;rsquo;m excited to finalize my plans to begin this journey!
Speaking of which, I bought my plane tickets today! First time I&amp;rsquo;ve ever bought a one-way flight. But it&amp;rsquo;s locked in now. I fly from Dallas to Washington D.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journal • 2015</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/albania/2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2015 21:36:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/albania/2015/</guid>
      <description>photo by Ron Acord  Day 1 Thursday July 2 Back for a third time! Kinda hard to believe we got 20 people. We have 2 teams full of great people and we&amp;rsquo;re here and ready to rumble. Will and Lauren are leading one team of 10 that&amp;rsquo;s staying in Tirana, while Lucy and I lead the team that will depart to Elbasan on Sunday. Getting here was much better than last year, thanks mostly to Lucy&amp;rsquo;s organizational leadership and Will&amp;rsquo;s being on the ball with prep.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Albania!  YEEEEHAWWW!</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/albania/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 22:20:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/albania/</guid>
      <description>What am I doing now? I&amp;rsquo;ve been working as a Software Developer for Watermark Community Church since September 2017. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of work to be done on various projects with the Church, and the job is flexible enough that I can continue to be involved in Albania!
We went back in December for a men&amp;rsquo;s conference, and we&amp;rsquo;re going back this summer as well. I&amp;rsquo;m leading the team that will work with the Young Professionals in the capital city of Tirana.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Euro Trip!</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2015/01_euro-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 10:20:47 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2015/01_euro-trip/</guid>
      <description>The best part is it&amp;rsquo;s only half over! I&amp;rsquo;m writing this post from the home of my good friend Aldo Rustemi, in Tirana the capital city of Albania. So much has happened, and so much more is to come. It&amp;rsquo;s awesome :)
Wien, Österreich We began the trip in Vienna, where we went sightseeing just the three of us (me, Lucy and Chris). Vienna in the winter is amazing, especially when there&amp;rsquo;s snow on the ground.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journal • 2014</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/albania/2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2014 21:36:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/albania/2014/</guid>
      <description>Travel Days July 12-13 We flew overnight on Austrian airways, leaving early morning on the 12th with a layover at Washington Dulles. We were all tired, but some of us were awake enough to go out to the National Air and Space museum Udvar-Hazy center for a couple hours. My dad decided to meet us there, since my parents live in Washington DC. He, my little sister Alina and I hung out with Will, Danita, and Ron at the museum, which was pretty awesome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journal • 2013</title>
      <link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/albania/2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2013 21:36:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/albania/2013/</guid>
      <description>Day 1 Thursday July 18 I don&amp;rsquo;t even know why God brought us down here. What more can we do that He&amp;rsquo;s not already doing? Today we got off the plane, and found out our luggage won&amp;rsquo;t arrive until tomorrow. We rode into town with a nice guy who picked us up. We were met at the hotel by Aldo, who is one of the leaders of Ice and Spice.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>