<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Development on first things first</title><link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/tags/development/</link><description>Recent content in Development on first things first</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>All content © Gordon Burgett, 2014-2015</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 14:52:15 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://www.gordonburgett.net/tags/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Feeling Like I'm at Hogwarts</title><link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2018/05_enrolled_at_hogwarts/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 14:52:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2018/05_enrolled_at_hogwarts/</guid><description>&lt;p>I spent some time this week playing with &lt;a href="https://www.typescriptlang.org/docs/handbook/release-notes/typescript-2-8.html">Typescript 2.8&amp;rsquo;s new features&lt;/a>
for modeling various complex types. The new syntax that I wanted to play with
was the conditional type syntax,&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-ts" data-lang="ts">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">T&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">extends&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">U&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">?&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">X&lt;/span> : &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">Y&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>This syntax allows you to express some really crazy type relationships! Some of
the most interesting ones have been pre-defined in the Typescript standard lib:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;code>Exclude&amp;lt;T, U&amp;gt;&lt;/code> – Exclude from T those types that are assignable to U.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>Extract&amp;lt;T, U&amp;gt;&lt;/code> – Extract from T those types that are assignable to U.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>I wanted to see if I could use these to model the way we&amp;rsquo;ve been working with
return values from &lt;a href="https://www.contentful.com/developers/docs/references/content-delivery-api/">Contentful&amp;rsquo;s Content Delivery API&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Modern Static Sites</title><link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2017/04_modern_static_sites/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 13:49:22 +0200</pubDate><guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2017/04_modern_static_sites/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today in 2017, there are a thousand and one different ways to build a website. As always there&amp;rsquo;s good old fashioned &lt;a href="https://wordpress.com">Wordpress&lt;/a>, and of course there&amp;rsquo;s drag-n-drop website builders like &lt;a href="http://www.wix.com">Wix&lt;/a>. One thing these have in common is that they need a traditional hosting environment, and for that you gotta pay.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you can manage it, the cheapest way to host a website nowadays is to create a static HTML site. But don&amp;rsquo;t hand-craft HTML, that&amp;rsquo;s hard and boring. Use a static site generator, for fun and profit!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Taking Control of My Data</title><link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2016/09_taking_control_of_my_data/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 15:33:34 +0200</pubDate><guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2016/09_taking_control_of_my_data/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of my projects during my vacation has been to take back control of my data. The question of online privacy is a difficult one, because while there&amp;rsquo;s some things you can do to improve your privacy, to really own your data takes a lot of effort and learning. For most people, hosting their own services is more headache than it&amp;rsquo;s worth. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of good privacy-conscious services out there if you&amp;rsquo;re willing to pay, but most people are not willing to pay. The convenience trumps the privacy concerns, and for me it has been that way for a long time as well.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Adventures in Dockerland</title><link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2016/02_adventures-in-dockerland/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2016 20:33:52 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2016/02_adventures-in-dockerland/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been on a serious docker/aws kick recently. I&amp;rsquo;ve learned just enough that it drives me to play with it. I spent a lot of my free time on it this week, and didn&amp;rsquo;t spend as much as I&amp;rsquo;d like on learning Albanian&amp;hellip; This could be a problem&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyways I might as well post more about what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned. I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to make my web server more robust, to where if it dies for whatever reason I don&amp;rsquo;t have to do anything, it&amp;rsquo;ll come back on a new instance all on its own. Unfortunately that&amp;rsquo;s a bit more difficult than you&amp;rsquo;d expect. Lots of moving parts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docker Cloud is Neat</title><link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2016/02_docker-cloud-is-neat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 14:09:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2016/02_docker-cloud-is-neat/</guid><description>&lt;p>I had some time off today so I decided to revisit how I&amp;rsquo;m hosting all my stuff. One of my issues with using Amazon&amp;rsquo;s container service is that they make you assign resource values to each container, and those are not flexible. So, I have to give each container high enough memory that it won&amp;rsquo;t die, but then I run out of space on my server real quick. Since most of the stuff I want to host just sits idle the majority of the time, this wasn&amp;rsquo;t ideal for me.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hosting Reclaimed</title><link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2016/01_hosting_reclaimed/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2016 21:31:01 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2016/01_hosting_reclaimed/</guid><description>&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s another technical post for y&amp;rsquo;all!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I had some time this past weekend, so I took a look into the website I made a year ago for &lt;a href="http://www.reclaimed431.org">Reclaimed&lt;/a>. The old version was made with &lt;a href="http://locomotivecms.com/">Locomotive CMS&lt;/a>, and hosted on &lt;a href="http://www.locomotivehosting.com">Locomotive hosting&lt;/a>. It was a good choice at the time, because we needed something fast. We wanted to deploy it before the 2015 super bowl.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;d previously looked into moving it to Wordpress or Drupal, but that would basically require redoing the whole site. More work than I&amp;rsquo;m willing to put in. But, just this past weekend, &lt;a href="http://locomotive.works/">Locomotive v3&lt;/a> came out. I decided to try hosting it myself, because $20/mo is just a bit too much to be paying for a simple website like this. Plus, it would be fun! (or so I thought.)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Running with Docker</title><link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2015/10_running_with_docker/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2015 20:33:41 +0200</pubDate><guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2015/10_running_with_docker/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="locked-out">Locked out!&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I managed to lock myself out of my EC2 instance when I was managing my keys. So in order to update my blog, I had to deploy it to a new EC2 instance. I decided to take the opportunity to improve the way I&amp;rsquo;m deploying new versions of my site.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Note: This will be a technical post. If you&amp;rsquo;re following along with my adventure in Albania, you can skip this one.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Migrating to Node</title><link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2015/04_migrating-to-node/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2015 23:23:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2015/04_migrating-to-node/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="so-i-wanted-an-app-server">So I wanted an app server.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>How hard could it be right? Well, not really that hard at all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was tired of having a static site served by apache. I want to do some cool stuff with the google APIs, like maybe a form submit where the results end up in a google doc for me. To do that I need more than hugo&amp;rsquo;s static site generation. But I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to get rid of hugo because I like a lot of it&amp;rsquo;s features, so I added nodejs on top of it as the application server.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>which which?</title><link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2015/01_which-which/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 22:49:08 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2015/01_which-which/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m using &lt;a href="http://locomotivecms.com/">locomotivecms&lt;/a> for a project I&amp;rsquo;m working on, and it uses &lt;a href="http://www.imagemagick.org/">ImageMagick&lt;/a> for resizing pictures on the fly. The &lt;a href="http://doc.locomotivecms.com/get-started/install-wagon#windows">standard instructions&lt;/a> say to use the bitnami Ruby stack installer to get everything you need in a nice neat bundle.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That worked for me for a while, until I needed to update the version of ruby I&amp;rsquo;m using. So, I went through the long and painful process of uninstalling the ruby stack, installing each component individually, identifying and correcting a ton of minor problems, and finally squashed the last bug by writing this program.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>hosting the blog</title><link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2014/12_hosting-the-blog/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2014 18:42:21 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2014/12_hosting-the-blog/</guid><description>&lt;p>I decided to use Amazon EC2 to host the blog, because they give you 1 year free on a micro instance. Plus I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to learn how to host something on Amazon&amp;rsquo;s cloud. I&amp;rsquo;ll get a linux instance and put an Apache HTTP server on it. Should be easy enough to do.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s my EC2 management console after signing up for an Amazon account and creating a linux micro instance:
![EC2 Management console](/images/2014/EC2 management console.png)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Creating a blog</title><link>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2014/12_creating-a-blog/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2014 13:52:12 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://www.gordonburgett.net/post/2014/12_creating-a-blog/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="well-here-it-is">Well, here it is.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to create a blog for a while. I don&amp;rsquo;t know what it will look like in the future, or how often I&amp;rsquo;ll update it, but as I sit here writing it it&amp;rsquo;s kind of cathartic. It would be good to get some thoughts out there, and if anybody reads it that&amp;rsquo;s a bonus.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I want to talk about anything and everything on this blog. I&amp;rsquo;ll delve into my work, hopefully some of these pages will be useful when another developer types some obscure error code into google. I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss my faith, hopefully that could spark some interesting discussion. I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss the important stuff that happens in my life, hopefully someone might find it interesting.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>